All right. What's going on?
>> Well, uh, that was interesting, I guess.
Uh, did anything about this process, was
anything about this process different
from before unique or difficult or
anything like that?
>> Uh, yeah, I'd say it was a little
different just, um,
being the second time. Obviously, the
situation's a little different. Um, but
you know, I thought uh I thought it was
it was good and and um I wanted to be
here. You know, made that clear to my
agents and and everybody and and um you
know, I'm glad it worked out. You know,
I said, you know, I'd just like to say
thanks to the to everyone involved, to
my agents, to the to Chris Ballard, Mike
Bloom, and and uh the team here, and
then obviously grateful uh to the URS
family and and uh this organization for
believing in me and giving me a chance
um you know, giving me a chance last
year to come in here, and then um
certainly this year. So, I'm I'm excited
and and thrilled to be back. This is a
special place with um you know really
really good people who who care about
football, care about winning, care about
the the um the players. So um yeah,
grateful to to the Ursa family, grateful
to this organization and um excited to
get back to work.
>> We got the transition the transition
tag. Was there ever a thought in your
mind that you could leave any?
Um, yeah, I think uh you certainly have
to consider uh the situation and and uh
what it means and and you know how it
could all play out. I think um so you
know that was discussed but always in
the context of I you know I want to be
here and and I made you know like I said
I made that clear to my my agents and
and um you know I made that clear to the
Colts as well and any communication I
had with them. So, I'm I'm glad it
worked out and and uh I'm thrilled uh to
be back.
>> When you want to be here and the Colts
want you here and then it takes a little
time. Does that get frustrating at all
as a player? Cuz I know obviously your
agents are handling negotiation, but
does it does it feel like a long time to
you or
>> Um
yeah, I mean, yeah, I think it's a
process. Um, you know, I think, uh, the
first time I kind of went through this,
I was probably a little bit more
involved than, um, than I was now, and,
you know, learned something through
that. I think this time I I I didn't
want to be as involved. I kind of let
my, you know, my my agents and and, um,
those guys, uh, directed and and
certainly, uh, communicated, but, um,
you know, trust them to to find the best
situation and, um, let it play out. So,
um, you know, I've focus on on what I
need to do, focus on my rehab and and
making sure I'm progressing every day
and then, uh, let them handle that
situation.
>> Was that something you kind of learned
the first time around that you didn't
really want to be all that involved with
it?
>> I think so. Yeah. I think um yeah, I
think you know there's a business side
of the of the sport and the game and um
you know let the professionals do that
with you know their job and and uh focus
on playing football, focus on in my
situation rehabbing and and making sure
I'm doing what I need to do. So um yeah,
I think that's something I I probably
learned the first time around. Daniel,
almost a year ago to the day you were
signing here, not knowing what the
future would hold, if you're even going
to win the job, and then you go out and
have the success you did. Could you just
describe your state of mind a year ago
up until today when you've known what
what all transpired in that time?
>> Yeah. Um, yeah, very different
situation. Um, for sure. and and uh
yeah, NFL, you know, playing quarterback
in the NFL, you know, I've you you see a
lot, experience a lot of different
things and and um learn a lot. So, um
you just try to learn through through
all those experiences and uh obviously
rather be in this situation than where I
was a year ago. But like I said earlier,
I'm grateful for the opportunity to come
in here and compete last year and for um
for Chris Ballard and and his group
believing in me, for Shane and and all
the coaches giving me a chance. And then
um yeah, very very grateful and
appreciative of that opportunity. And um
you know, I think you got to continue to
to to improve and and you're always
proving it. You're always uh competing
and and trying to improve as a player.
So, I don't think that approach changes
um at all.
>> Daniel, just one more thing on the
negotiation. Um you obviously have the
injury and those things always
complicate these matters. I mean, how
did you contextualize that and do do you
think that was something that had to be
confronted or dealt with, you know, then
during this process? Yeah, you know, I
can see um
you know, that's it's real, you know,
part part of the process and I
understand um the team has to take that
into to account. Um I'm very confident
in and uh you know, being back to 100%
and ready to go and um working every day
to do that. Have really good people
helping me get there. So um yeah, I'm
very very uh confident in that. But I
understand it's a consideration for the
team and they have to take that to into
into account.
>> You look like you're moving pretty good.
I mean, what how far have you come?
>> Uh yeah, I'm in a good spot. I think um
I'm on schedule. I think from everything
um doctors are telling me, trainers,
rehab, PTS. Um I think yeah, I I'm I'm
in a good spot. I've hit hit my marks
and just have to continue to do that.
It's a process. I understand, you know,
you kind of just keep checking the boxes
and keep progressing as you're, you
know, as the kind of the rehab protocol
uh lays out. So, I just just stick to
that. But I feel good with where I am
right now.
>> You say you're on schedule. What does
that mean? Like week one, I know you
talked about Democrat show getting ready
for week one, but how do you view
yourself getting ready for another
season?
>> Uh, yeah, I'm I'm confident I'll be
ready to go. I think uh my goal is to be
ready for week one. Um,
you know, with that being said, I
understand it is a process and there's
there's a lot of work to do, you know,
and uh, you know, I'm ready to do it.
So, I've got to continue to, like I
said, check the boxes, progress as the
doctors and, uh, and PTs and and, you
know, everybody instructs me and and my
job is to do the work and make sure I'm
I'm uh, consistent with that. So, uh,
that's what I'll do and and I think um,
if I continue to do that and and uh,
progress, I should be ready to go. You
tal you talked to some people who've
been through this Hallebertton and
Rogers and you said Cousins. Did any
great advice they give you? Is it kind
of like you want to push yourself but
not too hard? I mean, what what's the
balance of pushing yourself but not
doing too much too soon?
>> Yeah, I think um with this rehab, you
know, I did my knee a few years ago and
that was, you know, just starts a little
quicker from a rehab standpoint. you can
afford to be a little bit more
aggressive initially. I think with this
Achilles um there's an emphasis on on
being patient at least initially to uh
let the repair heal and and and uh kind
of set in place and then you know
there's a time to push it later on in
the process. So, um I think that's
advice you get from other people who
have gone through it from, you know,
advice you get from, you know, doctors
and and and PTs and, um I think that's
that's just yeah, kind of the difference
in in this rehab versus the last one.
But, um yeah, you pick up little things
along the way from talking to people
who've been through it. Um, but there's
all Yeah, I think there's always that
balance of uh making sure you're um
you're working as hard as you can and
pushing it within certain limits,
certain bounds that kind of are set
forward by the doctor or the rehab
protocol.
>> It feels like it feels like some guys
have made returns a little bit faster
than we're used to just kind of cross
Jason Tatum right now, the Celtics. Do
you notice that? Is it encouraging to
you that those guys are back out?
>> For sure. Yeah, I think um yeah, I think
you know the uh doctors, physical
therapists, everybody who's studying
this, you know, they're constantly
learning and and growing and and
understanding what helps recover quicker
and and you know, I try to learn as much
as I can from different uh different
doctors, different uh physical
therapists. You know, fortunate to be
working uh with the Colts here and and
you know, we've got great trainers,
great physical therapists um guiding,
you know, my process. So, uh, trusting
in in that and listening to it and while
also trying to learn as much as you can.
>> You I know you said it several times to
us at the end of the season and have
since Alec Pierce said the same about
wanting to be back here, not really
being that interested in looking
elsewhere. What was it about this last
year spent here in Indianapolis and with
the Colts that made you so certain about
not really wanting to look around or
explore elsewhere?
Um I think you know a big piece of it
the pe you know the people here and and
um enjoying uh enjoying working with
these coaches enjoying working with uh
my teammates. I think the the people on
the staff the trainers the um the
strength staff equipment staff everybody
um here you know it's been um been a lot
of fun to be here. I think um the
success on the field you know from from
uh the start we had and and how we were
performing um you know I think that you
know that's exciting and and and you
know you want to be a part of it. You
want to get back to that and and and
sustain it. So I think that's um I think
we all saw that and how good we can be
and we know there's a lot of work to do.
Uh, and every, you know, every group's
different, but, um, I think there's a
there's a good group of people here who
who work well together. Um, you know, I
can say I've really enjoyed working with
with Shane and his staff and and, um,
look to continue to to build on, um, a
lot of the things we made progress on
last year.
>> They brought back I mean, they're
bringing back you and and Alec who, you
know, the biggest pieces obviously, but
um, but there is a lot that goes into
taking the next step for any team. I
mean, you know, do you feel like you
guys are equipped to take that next
step? And, you know, your owner has even
said like, you know, we got to you want
to see something next year. Do you feel
like the team's equipped and prepared
for it?
>> I do. Yeah, I think um certainly
equipped and um you know, we understand
it starts over. we've got to prove it
again and and um and we got to build,
you know, this team and there's a lot of
work that goes into that just like there
was last year and and we've got to be
able to consistently perform and and do
that. So, um we're confident because I
think you know we've seen what you know
what we could be, but there's a high
sense of urgency to get back to to do
that and and and do that consistently
week after week um throughout the
season. So, um yeah, we certainly
understand that. We saw what you played
through last year and obviously what you
played through throughout your career,
but do the injuries ever creep into your
mind of just trying to be as durable as
you can throughout the season.
>> Um yeah, you know, I think um football's
a physical game. Um certainly had my
fair share of injuries uh through
throughout my career. Um but you know, I
think that that's part of it. But I work
hard to to keep my body in a good place
and and unfortunately at times you get,
you know, there's some some tough breaks
here and there, but um you know, I'm
confident, you know, I can stay healthy
and and protect myself. Um you know, and
and uh I'll you know, I think that's a
that's a a big deal. It's a big emphasis
of mine. You said Megan, you made it
clear that week one is your goal and
it's all hypothetical, but at what point
would you need to be like training camp
to where you're doing you're just not
going to roll out there in week one of
play. How much camp time do you think
you would need to be ease back into it
to where come week one you're ready?
>> Uh yeah, I'm not exactly sure at this
point. um you'd like to practice as much
as you can obviously going into to week
one and and um my goal yeah would be
would be that to practice
as much as I can during training camp
and and uh I think that's a realistic
expectation at this point.
>> You won't be ready for anything in
OTAAS.
>> Um
>> probably not.
>> Yeah, I think I I'll have to communicate
with the doctors and and trainers on
that. Um, I'd like to if I can, but you
know, you you you never know and it's a
process and and got to got to follow
that.
>> How do you think another step forward? I
know he's excited to get, you know, more
of the targets and be, I guess, a more
prominent feature in the offense.
>> Um, yeah, I mean, I think he's he's
capable and and has has the skill set to
um to do that and um you know, I think
last year um he did he did a lot of I
mean, he was he was obviously down the
field making plays um like he has his
whole career and then um made a lot of
plays in the intermediate game on, you
know, crossers and in cuts and you know,
deep outs and stuff like that and and
he'll continue to to do that for us. And
then um yeah, I think just continuing to
to feature him. Um I think he's he's uh
capable of of all of it. There's nothing
he he can't do from a router route or
receiver standpoint. So, it's uh our job
to get him the ball and um yeah,
confident and excited to get back to
work with him.
>> Chris,
>> you're the long-term answer here at
quarterback. What does that mean to you
to be wanted to be retained and to
obviously have a future here in
Indianapolis?
>> Yeah, it means a lot. Like I said, I I
really do appreciate um his belief in in
me and giving me a chance um to play and
uh you know, to be a part of this this
organization. I think um you know we do
have a great group of guys in the locker
room and a lot of talented uh football
players, a really a really good team and
and being part of that is is exciting
for me. It's exciting for all of us. So
um you know what what he's built and to
um yeah to the belief and faith I think
means a lot. I certainly uh you take
that seriously understand I've got to
continue to improve and grow and and
help this team uh achieve what we can.
you the first year in the system here
last year now I know you didn't finish
the season but having that opportunity
to have a full off season another
offseason I guess um with Shane in the
meeting room at least how much do you
think that will bear fruit on the field
this year you know you guys having time
on task to go
>> yeah I think it will will it will help
you know help a lot I think um you know
now we have the advantage of looking
back on things we did last year things
that worked and things that didn't and
then um you know say you know tweaking
in certain parts of that, adding things
that um you know that that uh marry up
with things we did last year that had
success and then um you know finding out
what didn't work as well and and moving
away from stuff like that. So I think
yeah just the advantage of of having a
season to look back on and learn from
and grow with and then um yeah just just
everybody um the communication and and
getting used to that having a season uh
behind us uh I think that'll help a lot.
>> Do you take a moment to
exhale or I don't know celebrated at
all. I mean you're eight years into this
now and earned a couple of contracts
like a hard sport. So have you had a
chance to just reflect it all?
>> Uh yeah I think uh this time of year
you're working hard and training but
it's not quite the same um stress that
you know the season is from just a time
and uh you know being being uh ready to
go. So, you know, you have some time to
reflect and and like I said, I'm very
grateful, very appreciative and and feel
very fortunate for uh to be here and all
the people who've helped me uh helped me
get here. I think um you know, I think
looking back just people who've
supported you along the way, coaches,
friends, family, and um yeah, very very
fortunate, grateful to those people. You
mentioned that you last gone through
this process before of earning and then
negotiating and landing a big deal um
and then and playing on that and
experiencing what goes uh what comes
next. What what did you learn from the
couple years after that first deal that
you landed in New York um that you'll
take with you through this next process?
I know there's probably some pressures
of um you know seeing the the
organization put all this faith in you.
How do you go about that and maybe what
did you learn from the first time
around?
Um, I think every situation's different.
Um, New York was was tough. Um, you
know, I got I Yeah. So, I mean, I think
you just you're constantly growing.
You're constantly improving the the
business side of it or the contract side
of it, you know, doesn't affect that and
doesn't, you know, doesn't affect your
mindset on on on uh yeah, how how do how
do you grow, how do you improve, how do
you help the team win? And um I think uh
you know I I know I'm able to do that
and and uh that continues to be the
focus.
>> Thanks Daniel.
>> Thanks. Thanks.